The
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): closer you've been following your equity investments recently, the jumpier you likely are. A lot of Americans have concluded that the Wall Street game may be rigged. The whole thing is kind of a scam, but there's still a huge amount of money tied up in it, not just in individual investing, of course, but in pension funds. The whole world is tied up in the American stock market. So how exactly do you succeed in it as
Speaker 2: an individual? We thought the man to ask would be the man who's seen
Speaker 2: sides of this
Speaker 3: business legitimate and less than Jordan Belfort the Wolf of Wall Street with a new book The Wolf of Investing and he joins us now to explain you
Speaker 4: can make a fortune
on
Speaker 5: Wall Street but it takes time yeah I think I
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): think listen the mistake that people make is that the average person is that you don't have that much money to start let's just choose a number let's say just
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): $10,000 right it's a random number right you say to yourself
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): If I'm going to really get anywhere as an investor, I need to make a big hit.
Speaker 8: I'm going to turn that into like a million bucks. I've got to find the next Apple computer, the next crazy
Speaker 9: crypto token, right? Whatever it might be, some wildly successful investment, right? Which leads you to engage in, you know, wild speculation,
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): short-term trading, trying to time the market. And the truth is, is the opposite. You don't need to start with a lot of money.
To
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): end up with a lot of money by doing the exact
Speaker 10: opposite, which is holding for the long term and all the highest quality stocks and relying on long term compounding and reinvesting dividends and making small contributions along the way. But forgetting, like you said, the noise and people are worried about their equities. This is the problem, because as soon as you start buying into that, like.
Speaker 10: You know what, I think the market might be going down or maybe it's going to go up next year. You just have to time that by buying and selling, you create taxable events. And also, human beings, by our nature, we're kind of crappy stock pickers. And when you try to pick individual stocks, you tend to lose most of
Speaker 11: the time.
Speaker 12: Wait, okay, so here's
Speaker 13: what I'm going to do. I'm going to give you my investment strategy, and I'm going to be as honest as I can be. And you assess it based on your expertise and tell me if I'm right or wrong. Okay, so...
Speaker 13: I'll get out of my rec room, big screen TV with my dab
Speaker 15: pen and my laptop and I'll turn on Jim Cramer on CNBC.
And
Speaker 2: when he tells me to buy, I buy.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): And if he says sell, I sell. Yeah. You're getting financially whipsawed. Is that working for me?
Speaker 17: No, it's not going to work. So I kind of buried Cramer in the book. I guess I'm not going on CNBC anytime soon for any interviews.
Why
Speaker 18: would you bury Jim Cramer? I mean, this is a guy with an uninterrupted string of correct calls. Buy...
Speaker 19: J.P. Morgan.
Speaker 19: of this
Speaker 20: generation, Sam Bankman-Fried's FTX. -
Speaker 21: Listen, the best thing was, was it interrupted the
Speaker 10: string of terrible calls. But listen, he's had a lot of good calls 'cause he's on both sides of the market. He tells you to buy one thing on Monday and sell it on Wednesday and back and vice versa. This guy literally is telling you, they actually did a study on this where they put up his recommendations of what he said on Monday and then on Friday. The exact opposite. Like one day he's saying the market's going up, next day it's going down, buy this, go from
Speaker 22: this sector to that sector.
Speaker 22: That's a historically, mathematically, scientifically proven to be the worst possible way to invest your money. They've gone back 100 years, the scientific, the academic studies and the analysts can't pick the right stocks. The hedge fund managers and the mutual fund managers
Speaker 10: can't beat the S&P 500, which is the overall broader market. And there's a reason for that, because all the information is out there.
So unless you have
Speaker 10: Inside information which is illegal right and certainly the average person is not going to have that or some other way To beat the mark whether it's a high frequency train with computers that are
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): lightning fast So some of the big firms they'll time the market like a millionth of a second better than an average investor They get an edge, but for everyone else you can't beat the market You just it doesn't work, especially when you deduct all the fees and
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): the commissions and also the taxes from short-term trading so let's say let's say a hedge fund returns 15 when you say that's pretty good right but after they take their two percent majesty 20 performance bonus
Speaker 8: right suddenly it's not even beating the s p 500 and that's in a good year most of the time
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): they don't even beat it without their fees so why would anyone hand money to a hedge fund so warren buffett asked this exact question back in 2007 made a big announcement that a million bucks
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): that I don't care whatever hedge fund you want, you can't beat the S&P for a hundred over 10 years. And at first, no one took the bet. Eventually someone did with
Speaker 10: what's called a fund of funds. It was a hundred different funds, right? And after year seven, they threw in the towel. They couldn't even come close to the S&P. And that was without all their fees. And just so you know, the fees they take. So it's 20% typically is a performance bonus, right? If the fund makes money- - Off the upside. - On the upside, but if the fund loses money the following
year,
they
Speaker 10: don't get any of the losses so it's heads they win tails you lose right the mutual fund industry is equally bad so they're engaging in you know basically asset gathering because what they do is they try to gather as many assets as possible money right because they get their management fees but the returns on the average mutual fund are dismal they don't keep up with the S&P 500 which is America's 500 biggest baddest
most
Speaker 22: profitable companies so and that those 500 companies change so not this yes view this year is not the same as it was last year so what happens when you buy that index as the centerpiece of your
Speaker 10: investments right and just hold it you're always having the 500 top high performing companies in your portfolio is very tax efficient
Speaker 22: now it's boring
but
Speaker 22: it compounds at about 11% a year. And guess what? If you invest $10,000,
Speaker 10: right? And just compounds at 11% a year, you put a little extra money in whenever you can each
Speaker 22: month, each quarter, right? Over 30 years, 40 years, it turns into millions of dollars.
Speaker 24: But I'm still caught up in the hedge fund idea.
Speaker 24: So, Steve Cohen, Ray Dalio, all these guys are billionaires. Right. World's biggest art
Speaker 25: collection. So how did they get so rich if it doesn't work?
Well,
Speaker 10: for a time, it was like everyone thought, "Oh my God, they're so great, the hedge funds." So for many in the '90s and 2000s, the word was really like this mystique that you had these really high-performing hedge
Speaker 26: funds, and there were a few. There were a few people that actually can beat the market. Ray Dalio is one who's done it consistently. He's not taking your money.
Speaker 26: When they're really not good, they don't take the average investor's money. They train their own money in
Speaker 10: a few very, very large institutions. So those funds are not open to the average investor. But then all the other hedge funders kind of suck, right? They're bathing in the afterglow of the aura of the hedge fund manager we see on billions, right? See this mystical hedge fund? Well, guess what?
Most of
Speaker 10: these guys suck.
Speaker 10: all right they they're not beating the s they're just not it's mad it's historically proven they don't beat the s&p and they take these massive fees when they do win one year and they always get that two percent magically so watch what happens let's say you're managing a billion dollars so before you even start there's 20 million a year you're getting just in it with 40 even starts plus 20 of all the profits and when you take those and how about this i'll go one step further and also when you have a hedge fund you have to show activity because unless you're you can't just
Speaker 10: buy the S&P and hold it some will say well why would I give you my money you're not doing anything so they almost have to show activity
Speaker 22: to justify their existence which makes them engage in short-term trading and people human beings are just terrible market timers they and this is just over it's proven over a hundred plus years of studies that
Speaker 10: you cannot trade in and out of the stock market buying selling selling buying sector this sector one day so it's just a trap the way I look at it is this a wall street
Speaker 10: creates massive value. They do. Wall Street's necessary. You can hate Wall Street,
Speaker 22: despise them for what things they do wrong, but Wall Street is necessary. They create massive value for the economy. They take companies public, right? They finance the growth of America. It's needed.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): They maintain the debt markets, the credit markets. That's the useful side of Wall Street where they create massive value.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Then there's the not so useful, the dark side of Wall Street, where they create bubble after
Speaker 9: bubble after bubble, where they have instruments of financial mass destruction they create for just gambling purposes, where they churn you, they have excess commissions and fees and rob the public blind. So the question in the book was, you know, how does the average person get the maximum exposure to the good side of Wall Street, which is the great companies they take public and finance that become huge multinational. So how do you maximize that?
Speaker 9: But avoid the corruption, all the churning and the burning and the financial bubbles and so forth and play into what I call the Wall Street Fiend Machine Complex, which is this advertising monolith where basically they convince you, like people like Kramer, to play the sucker's game. Actively, if you go on CNBC, they're all day long trying to convince people to play the short-term trading game, which is indeed a sucker's game.
So
Speaker 9: you go into a casino, right? We spoke about about Kerry Packer, right? Because gambling, right? So they own
Speaker 22: casinos, the Packer family, right? So in a casino, you go in there knowing that the odds are against you by what? 5% depending on what game you play.
So
Speaker 9: the odds are against you in the house will win over time, right? That's a legit casino. The odds are against you. But what if you go into a corrupt casino?
Speaker 9: where they have loaded dice and a dealing from the bottom of the deck. That's Wall Street. So now not only are the odds against you because you know, it's hard to pick winning stocks, but there's people who have information that's more timely than you. They're trading ahead of you. They are charging excess fees and also you have all these publications and new chatting in news with CNBC, Bloomberg isn't as bad because they cater mostly to professionals, but still trying to convince people.
Speaker 9: that, you know, you could somehow figure out when you should buy oil and then sell your meta and then somehow go into a steel stock and then go into overseas.
Speaker 22: It's insane. It doesn't work. And people get financially whipsawed. And I saw it myself, my own family member, very successful guy. I start my book off telling his story. That's your brother. Yeah, my brother. He's a very smart guy. And he's what
I
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): watched his portfolio get.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Decimated through short-term trading and using margin all the things that they was he doing it himself He's trying to do it himself and you know following tips He heard on TV or online
Speaker 22: and and it's just and it's so simple what
Speaker 27: happened to him?
Speaker 22: Well, he's thankfully he successfully lost a lot of money and then he learned his lesson I showed him what to do the right way and he now is building a proper portfolio for the long term So I think the distinction is this you can get rich in the stock market, but not overnight and
Speaker 22: it's just it doesn't work you can't do that and if you try to get rich by engaging in short-term trading or picking like one stock you're probably going to end up in the financial poorhouse so the solution i put in this book
Speaker 9: which is ironically where i came from right because i committed fraud 30 years ago right so as you said i've seen
both
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): sides right so the solution in the book is is really very simple to build a world-class portfolio and secure your future because i don't think you can rely on social
Speaker 22: security these days you don't have to pay for your diapers when you're in a nursing home, by the time you get it,
Speaker 22: Right. So this is about, you know, empowering yourself financially. And it's about doing less versus more, not hiring experts. Less
trading
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): yourself, less trade. It's about investing as opposed to speculating. Now, there's nothing wrong with
Speaker 22: speculating. It's fun. Right. And if you want to take 5% of your capital and speculate and buy and sell it, that's great. There's nothing wrong with that. Now, I encourage people to do that because it's good. You can have fun with that. Maybe you'll make some money.
Speaker 22: but that's not how you secure your retirement if you want to secure a great retirement you start off young as possible right and it's never too late by the way and it doesn't
Speaker 9: matter how much money you have you can start with a little bit of money you don't need a lot but the key is making little small regular contributions and not worrying an index
Speaker 29: fund is that what you're
the
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): main one is an index fund you want to have an index on s p low cost s p 500 index fund and
Speaker 22: you want to have it in certain types of accounts that are tax deferred whenever possible and so so forth, right?
Then you also
Speaker 22: want to balance that out with some you need to have some bonds in there a small amount depending on your age right and on top of that some cash for an emergency and then if you want to speculate you can have let's say five percent for speculation but the key is this don't
Speaker 9: hire an expert for example we've been conditioned this is the trap right so you're a homeowner right so if your your pipes in your house burst you probably do a lot better off calling a plumber
to
Speaker 9: fix your pipes then trying to fix them yourself right right right fair enough
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): right if you have electric short i suggest you call an electrician versus trying to go put on rubber gloves and not get electrocuted you'll get a much better result with the expert in that too if you're sick so your appendix is about
Speaker 9: to burst right don't do your own surgery have your wife cut you open go to a doctor that's an expert at doing surgery let him do
the
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): surgery fair fair enough right that's true for almost all things in life except wall street
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): It's the one exception to the otherwise pretty much
Speaker 22: steadfast rule about seeking out experts to help you get the best result on Wall Street. They don't get you a better result than doing it yourself. They get you a worse result because of all the fees, the commissions, the performance bonuses and also they
Speaker 30: can't outguess the market. The market is too hard to beat. Now again, there's a few people that can do it. They're not taking your money.
I
Speaker 14: want to focus on them for a second because undoubtedly they're the touts. They're the people who convince the rest of us that this works
Speaker 31: because they're so rich.
How did
Speaker 31: those people get rich?
So a guy like,
Speaker 32: for example, like Ray Dalio, he got in
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): very early into the game, right? And he's an incredibly brilliant guy. He's a great stock picker. And whatever his proprietary method is or a Warren Buffett, right? know these there's a few people out there and this is one of
the great
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): studies was from an economist named Paul Samuelson right in the 70s and this is really what started the shift into index funds he did a study that went back a hundred years all the way to the earliest days of record-keeping right study every mutual fund out there since the 1920s all
Speaker 9: the stock recommendations since 1890s right and he came to the conclusion he goes okay maybe there were a few people who can outperform the
S&P
But
Speaker 9: they remain remarkably well hidden. He
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): couldn't find any. This is like a top, like he won a Nobel Prize, the guy for this, right? So that was really the beginning. That was like the shot across the bow. Now, Wall Street did everything they could to suppress
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): this. So the first guy to try this was Jack Bogle from Vanguard. You know, Vanguard, right? So Vanguard is a great place where you can buy the best index funds with virtually no expense. So I strongly recommend Vanguard, right? And there's a few others as well. But Jack Bogle was the first, right? Right.
But
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): when he started Vanguard, Wall Street went out on the ultimate
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): smear campaign for like a decade, suppressing everything about index funds, saying it's the stupidest thing.
Who
Speaker 30: wants to be average? Dreyfus, which is a huge mutual company, said no fees, no way. Like actually in the Wall Street chart, a full page is like if you don't like that was marketed to the people who were the gatekeepers to investors. So yeah, because Vanguard doesn't pay fees, right? So if they
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): don't pay you fees, don't put your clients in their funds. Instead,
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): put them in our high commission funds will pay you a lot of money so for many many years vanguard languished and was suppressed right it
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): finally got traction after the crash in 87 for the first time all of a sudden you know the mirage evaporate when everyone lost a lot of money and for the first time
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): vanguard started to get a fair shake in the market and then slowly but surely they start to grow and grow and then as the internet
Came
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): about in the high speed connections and platforms for direct communications with
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): customers. It suddenly became a mass exodus out of these like, you know, sort of high expense mutual funds. Right. Which
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): I think that Bogle saved the public probably a few hundred billion by now in fees. Mutual funds were ripping people's eyeballs out.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): forever now they still do crappy their performance is crappy compared to the s p 500 but for years and years they're just ripping the public's eyeballs that was the most lucrative industry out there and wall street just spent you know countless hundreds of millions on advertising campaigns and whatnot right to make people think this is the way to go
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): So your Merrill Lynch is bullish on those
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): commercials, bullish
Speaker 22: on America, right? Although, you know, a T. Rowe price. I want to point the thing at any one of them, right? But now they all offer this ultra low cost index options, which
Speaker 9: historically has outperformed people trying to pick individual stocks.
Speaker 9: forever just it outperforms people because people are really crappy at
Speaker 22: picking stocks and also you know there's another part to it as well right just trying to time the market it plays
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): into all our worst impulses so like you said right now people are scared right and rightfully so the world seems to be on fire and you know i watch your podcast all
Speaker 9: the time and it scares me sometimes it's a scary world right so you would think that okay the
Speaker 22: u.s economy is laden with debt
Speaker 22: Right, which is true, right? It's got fundamental problems. China's gonna take over the world, right? Well, what I was you know in just getting started was Japan taking over the world which turned to be a fallacy and they had their
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): own problems So I don't know whether China is gonna take over the would be the biggest economy It's gonna surpass the United States. I don't know if the stock market's
Speaker 22: gonna go up down Sideways around circles for the next five years.
I mean
Speaker 22: how do you don't know anyone tells you they know that is lying to you and
So
Speaker 22: to sit there and try to watch the news and trade against like what's happening in the economy and what's happening in the world is a fool's errand. You're not going to succeed like that unless you're one of these rare individuals who's full time as this unique gift. So but then again, though, look at all these massive companies that have been created in the last 20 years, like, you know, Google, Meta, right? This is a huge
Speaker 35: company that in the video with artificial intelligence. So how do you get exposure to all that?
Speaker 35: without having to pick the winners from the losers the answer is very simple you buy them
Speaker 22: all in one investment which is the s p 500 and then you sit back and let time do the heavy lifting
Speaker 8: for you so you don't have to watch jim kramer at all if you watch jim kramer for entertainment if you like that kind of bloviating humor good for you right i personally don't like it the worst even worse than that is if you watch jim kramer and you happen to
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): opt in like if you have
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): to answer to one of the emails on the website, they'll start barraging you with email.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): I did this as an experiment, like I was like, you know, a guy that injects up with the virus to see how sick you get, right? I actually opted into Kramer's, you know, little thing online and I started receiving a barrage
of
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): like a hundred emails about
Speaker 22: join his special club. He'll alert you to what stocks are going up and down in real time. I mean, it's like, this is insanity, but this is a major network, right? That's,
you
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): know, giving investors crappy advice.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): Now, on the flip side, here's the weird part. They also have good stuff on that network, like there's legitimate news. And that's the
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): problem. So they mix in legitimate news, great reporting, interviews with great CEOs, and you learn about the economy, what's going on in the world. But they
Speaker 22: intersperse that with like this market giving advice.
Speaker 22: and it's not it's nonsense you you people can't beat the market and i saw it play out my brother-in-law many of my friends
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): back in when the bubble burst in 2008 and even worse by the way in 2000 with the dot-com bust right so every time
Speaker 26: the market busts out all the bullshit gets exposed
Speaker 36: of course and
Speaker 26: all of a sudden people thought they were expert day traders or expert market timers
they were
Speaker 26: like basking in the glove just an up market like i say in the book a rising tide lifts all ships
Speaker 26: right and a falling tide well it lowers all ships right so
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): you see the truth come out as one puppet says you know until the tide goes out you don't know who's not has no clothes on who's swimming naked so
Speaker 38: but you said at the outset that there are people who do
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): succeed in the market because they have inside information right it feels like there's a lot of that there is yeah how does that work
so I think
Speaker 39: there's different levels of it right there's like the
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): full-on criminal
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): Stuff like you saw in the movie Wall Street Gordon Gekko right where like people are actually paying people and moles and stuff like that to get You know information. It's not public paying off directors having inside links to the company or law firms that are doing deals Right that happens for sure and people do get
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): in trouble from time to time and go to jail Right, but Martha Stewart not exactly right, but she was like kind of you know a full person She sure was like a meal
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): people did a lot worse than Martha
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): Stewart, right? I mean, why do you put her away? You know, it's hard to say, but she's, you know, famous and she's a big target and, you know, it kind of sucks when you're famous
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): in a big target and they want to come get you, right? Especially if some of your views aren't that popular. They want to come after you, right? So, but that's sort of the cliched type of insider trading where they're just literally buying and getting moles and that's highly illegal.
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): Then there's the softer side of it, which is where these big hedge funds have these like analytical
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): firms that are getting like research that's inside research. So like, for example, they're like I had a friend who was a very big short seller, right? And he actually had people waiting outside of a warehouse counting the number
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): of trucks that were leaving
Speaker 26: the warehouse to try to like you get it to see how they really shipping the amount of goods to do this deep.
Speaker 26: type of research, which sometimes
Speaker 39: crosses over into inside information. So what is the line? I mean, you're allowed to be informed. You're allowed to be informed. But theoretically, you should
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): not be in possession of information that is nonpublic. Everyone's supposed to have access to the same information at the same time to make a fair market. Right.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): And generally speaking, it's true for everybody, all the average investors, but there are certainly people on Wall Street. I mean, you'd be naive to think that, you know, an analyst that has special relationships that's
Speaker 26: doing the investment banking deal. So if someone raises, you know, $500 million for a company, you tell me the CEO and the owner of that firm are not like having little conversations, little inklings here and there. So I'm sure that's happening. That's much more...
Speaker 26: difficult to prove. So it's a lot
of
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): it is buried under like, you know, guidance in financial reports. So the issue in our report, right. And you know,
the
Speaker 8: answer for will give sort of plausible deniability for why they think a stock is going up or down. Right. But even then, I mean, I think that's difficult to prove, which is why you don't hear a lot of those cases.
Speaker 43: No, the SEC doesn't seem to bring
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): any. Well, yes, I have the whole history of the SEC in the book. The SEC is a ridiculous organization. So it was conceived. Listen, the first chairman was was was was Jack Kennedy.
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): you know or joe joe kennedy the original wolf yeah so like
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): you know the bootlegger yeah from the beginning it was set up with a two-tiered system where the big firms basically were protected right and you know when they got in trouble they did things so egregious that it was undeniably egregious they'd
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): pay a small fine and move on right which is why goldman sachs for example right now goldman sachs
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): is serves a vital function to the US economy. And
Speaker 22: they're also behind every great crime or the biggest crimes that are out there, including my movie. That was the Wolf of Wall Street was financed by these Malaysians, right? The one NDB fund, that scandal. That was
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): just coincidentally. And who was the banker that that paved the way for that? Goldman Sachs out of there, I think was in Malaysia or Singapore office that a banker that provided the funding and, you know,
got
Double
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): or triple the normal fees
Speaker 22: for doing it and that money got siphoned off. That's classic Wall Street So on one hand they create massive value on the other hand they rape and pillage the village and it's the average investor and the average person that bears the brunt
Speaker 45: of that the bailouts and subpar returns so Just to follow up on the Wall Street investment firm. I mean information firms research. Yeah I
mean
Speaker 45: everyone uses
Speaker 46: those correct right hedge funds are very much using them so
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): they got in trouble though in the past in some cases they pay employees or former employees of companies to talk about what's happening inside the company right and that's very common yes that's
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): so that's simply the lobbyists how is that not in-center
Speaker 48: trading i've always wondered
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): well again it's it's
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): not if someone gives you an overall you know sense of what's going on that's like nothing that's not out in the public domain but it's sort of like
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): an insider's perspective versus information on like our sales going down. Is there a problem with manufacturing? It's not public. Right. So that's
Speaker 26: when it crosses over the line and it's a gray area. Right. But it's very common in hedge funds to use these research firms that go out there and get non public
Speaker 9: information. And there's a very fine line like a drug trial.
Speaker 9: There's a drug trial going on, like, you know, how do you know how the drug trial is performing?
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): Well, if you imagine calling up all the people or interviewing people that are in the drug trial and trying to figure out yourself, or people are intimately involved with administering the placebo studies, the double blind studies, they're all over
Speaker 3: that stuff. It appears that members of Congress consistently beat the S&P 500 in their personal investments. Nancy
Pelosi.
Speaker 49: And a lot of others, Pelosi especially. She's the famous one. Yeah. So how does that, is Nancy Pelosi, do you think, a stock picking genius?
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): No, she has to be operating on information that's non-public or is it not. Wouldn't that make
Speaker 51: her a criminal?
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, but, you know,
look at
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): Joe Biden right now. I mean, look what's
Speaker 52: going on right now. Like, listen. Do you think he's a good stock picker? Joe Biden? No, I think he's great at laundering money, though. Yeah, apparently.
I mean, honestly. From
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): what I've seen right now, I don't get it. Like, just imagine if it was Trump who was president. Yeah. Every single day in the front
Speaker 9: page of the New York Times, the Washington Post, and every other publication would be like $40,000 check for $20,000 check from his
his
Speaker 9: brother like it'd be game over cries for impeachment oh yeah it'd be like the world falling down he's in china's pocket
but
Speaker 8: it's like we're living in an alternative universe right now where
Speaker 26: people in power especially on the on the left right can operate almost with impunity and pelosi is a perfect example she's
not the
Speaker 26: only one but it's inconceivable that someone could have that high return on the mark when everyone else can't do it so what's the edge the edge is she knows but let key legislation also you know maybe someone's whispering in her
ear
Speaker 26: here, okay? You know, they want to be on our good side, right? So it's hard to
Speaker 49: prove though. But it's just prima facie. So if what you're saying is true and that is that the most sophisticated people in the world can't beat the S&P average, then any member of Congress, and I think they are on average dumber than the population- Especially
the
Speaker 22: career politicians. For sure.
Speaker 49: There's no possibility
Speaker 55: they could do that with that inside information.
Speaker 22: No, it's not possible. But again So how do you go proving that right that the issue subpoenas and
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): listen I think that the in this case the solution is they shouldn't be allowed to trade these people. Yes, they should not be allowed
to trade
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): it's insane that they're allowed to and You know, as you said, it's prime facie, right? You know, if it looks like shit smells like shame Well, guess what? Yeah, it's shit. Then that's you know, or is bullshit in this case, right? So listen, she's done incredibly well and
in
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): an area where, like, the most professional investors struggle to even match the index. So
Speaker 56: somehow she's doing three times as well. I don't know.
Why is no one
Speaker 56: ever taking that seriously? I mean, this is like a feature
Speaker 57: of Internet memes, but I don't know. I mean, don't we have an SEC to look into that? SEC is not going
Speaker 58: to look into that sort of stuff because they don't want
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): to make an enemy because they're funded. Who funds them? You know, they're funded by Congress. The budget's tied to Congress, right? There's a committee, it's the Financial Services Committee,
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): So that funds the SEC. But
Speaker 59: how does it make you feel? I mean, you got in a lot of trouble for fraud. But I deserved it. Right, but so do they.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, I know. But I never... One thing... Listen, I admit that after 2008, I got a little bit bitter. I was like, you know what? These people have bankrupted the world economy. And no one went to jail, basically. So one schnook in Germany went to
Speaker 58: jail. So I was a little... I said, you know what? That's not really fair. But, you know, I don't think it's...
you
Speaker 60: know an empowering way to live to say just because you know i went to jail other people
Speaker 26: should go too i think jail is a terrible place right and um you know i did my time and um and i made the best that i wrote my first book in jail right which turned to be a great thing but you know i learned from that but i don't then wish it on how
Speaker 61: did you i mean a lot of people go to jail
Speaker 62: few write books how did you how did you do that it's a great story so believe it or not when i go to jail right how old are
you
Speaker 62: I was 41 years old for you. Yeah, it's terrible time to go to jail. Right. I lost everything. Right. And it goes by two kids at the time. Yeah, which
Speaker 63: was breaking the news to them was the most heartbreaking thing ever. I mean, like, literally, it was like, too much
Speaker 26: crying. And then you go, I still get emotional about it. Right. And I
had to tell
Speaker 26: them, like, you know, daddy made mistakes. And that was hysterical. They were 11 and nine at the time.
Speaker 26: So I go to jail and it's not the worst jail in the world. I'm not worried about slipping
in the
Speaker 26: shower. So it's like a minimum security, but jail sucks, right? Who's my bunkmate? Tommy Chong from Cheech and Chong. What was he doing there? So he's there for selling not marijuana, but bongs. It was the most ridiculous thing ever.
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): So he's doing a year and a day, a year and a day.
for
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): selling bonds i'm like he's doing a year and a day for bonds i should probably get three thousand years
Speaker 65: how long how long are you serving i'm 22 months
Speaker 66: yeah right so he's there for a year and a day and you know the first few days you
Speaker 26: know there's not much to just tell each other stories and i'm telling him stories about my life being sandy and did you know who he was of course yeah they put us together we shared a special
Speaker 67: yeah because they were both high profile so they just put us together right so they could watch us both at once
Speaker 65: right so in jail as in normal life all the the famous people know each other basically right so he's a
Speaker 26: great
he's a great
Speaker 26: great guy. And he was he was writing a book at the time. And I'm telling him stories. And he's just rolling, just laughing hysterically every
Speaker 35: night. Right. And the third night, he's like, you know, I'm making this shit up. But my wife Googled you. And it's like all true. In fact, your assistant knows you from her father from back in the day. He was a friend of my right. He's like, this is you actually sank the boat. You crashed these cars. You did all this insane. You made all this money and all these drugs. You have to write a book. And I'm
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): like, really?
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): You think my life's exciting? Like, because it's your life. No matter how crazy your life is, it's yours. You don't think, right? You think it's just normal. I'm like, he's like, I'm Tommy Chong. I think your life is just insane. He goes, write a book. So I started trying to write, and I was a terrible writer. Terrible. I couldn't write anything. I'd never written before like that, you know? So after like a month, I'm like, oh, this is just not working. I go to the prison library, and I stumble upon a book called Bonfire of the Vanities by Tom Wolfe. Of course. I pick up this book, and I'm like...
oh
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): my god I want to write like this so I plowed through the book and then I started with the yellow highlight and I used this book like a textbook and I taught myself to write by modeling Tom Wolfe so it's like I had a model now and I spent about three months just every I mean every metaphor how he used
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): grab how he described locations how he used conflict and I really started to see my writing dramatically improve so I wrote about a hundred pages when I was in jail and then
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): I ripped them up, I didn't think
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): they were good enough. I got out of jail with no pages, but I had a skill now, right? So when I got out,
I was
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): like, you know, I don't know what to do with my life. And I was like, maybe I'll just start trying to write again, right?
So I
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): wrote about 12 pages and I'm like, wow, I think those are really good. I thought they were pretty good
and I
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): hate my own writing always, right? It's like when you write, it's very, like you always hate what you write, right? So I'm like, I think this is pretty good. I sent them to a few friends and they're like laughing, like, oh my God, it's the funny, I'm like, really? So I sent it to a book agent I knew very casually, just a casual friend, right?
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): So I call him and say, I want to, you know, write a book. He goes, oh great, let's get you a ghostwriter. I said, well, I want to write myself. He goes, can you write? I'm like, I'll send you the pages. I sent him 12 pages. Next day he calls me back. He goes, did you pay Tom Wolfe to write those pages? It was that close to Tom Wolfe's voice, my first draft, right? I'm like, no, no, I wrote it myself. He's like, it's really good. He goes like, write 10 more pages. So I said, all right. So it took me a week to write 10 more pages. I wrote another 10 pages. I sent him the pages. 15 minutes later he calls. He goes, stop everything you're doing.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): You have no idea what's about to happen to your life. This book is going to be a master head master. I'm going to get a movie made about this. We're going to get Leo DiCaprio to play you right me right from the start. Right. I was like, I thought it was delusional. Right. But I didn't have much going on back then. Right. So I was like, screw it. So I hold up and literally I had a little tiny apartment and I spent one year.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): Just like doing 18 hours a day writing the book The Wolf of Wall Street right about on page 60 he took it down to Random House who bought the book I got a nice advance to like at least live right and then when the book was finished about a year later went through seven edits because I overrode it got it from a thousand pages down to 500 pages and then when it was still a manuscript became a bidding war between Brad Pitt
and Leo DiCaprio
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): Yes, it wasn't a book yet. I know it's crazy right and then you know Leo brought in Scorsese and I would love Leo so I sold to Leo and Scorsese after a nice bidding war and So began, you know the story of the Wolf of Wall Street What happened with the movie and then there was a delay by the way for five years because that was 2007 and then the writer strike it
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): and it got delayed
and
Speaker 7 (lower-pitched voice): Which ended up being a great thing and this is really empowering for all the listeners I'll tell you why because when I when they wrote the script when the script was done by a guy named Terry winter Who adopted the book? He
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): did an incredible job the first draft of the script was amazing, right? But it ended with me in jail Like because I went to jail and got out right and that was the ending of the movie of the script, right? There was this delay then for four years after the writer's strike and
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): during those four years I got very wealthy again going out there and speaking and training entrepreneurs and teaching sales right so finally four years later when Leo called because we're ready to go he came back to my new
house I
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): was living in a mansion on the woods like what the hell happened to you like in four years I was in a tiny apartment now into a very nice house again and like oh I'm do this stuff around the world I showed him my clips from live on stage he's like wait till Marty sees this he's gonna go crazy they rewrote the third act of the movie and made it a comeback story
so
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): that's
Speaker 68: yes i kind of rewrote my life story when
Speaker 69: were you happier at the peak of your success pre-conviction
Speaker 45: or on the comeback comeback i was never happy before why number one i was
a
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): massive drug addiction yeah like i'm literally massive drug addiction what were you using quaaludes and cocaine
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): quaaludes yes this is the 70s 70s well you know i i where'd you get quaaludes i'll tell you how so we when i got really wealthy you know they made them illegal in the united states yeah - It could go a long time ago.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): But in Switzerland and Italy and Spain, we were going country to country and like buying out the pharmacies of all the ludes from overseas
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): and bringing them back into the United States, just not to sell them, just to take them, just to eat them all. We weren't dealing them, just consuming massive quantities of these quaaludes, right? And I got so wildly, I mean, I was taking about 10,
Speaker 73: 12
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): a day. You get
Speaker 73: very deep.
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): And like one of them would knock out a 200 pound Navy seal for eight
Speaker 74: hours. I would take four and walk around like what was the appeal of that,
Speaker 50 (lower-pitched voice): you know,
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): euphoria, the incredibly euphoric. They get this like the first thing you get this tingle phase and then you get the slurs and the happy
Speaker 75: drool phase. And anyway, it's incredibly euphoric. And then I said, well, what's the drool phase?
Speaker 52: The drool phase is when you're drooling as you're talking, but you're like, well, drooling is not a big deal. Babies
Speaker 26: drool. And when you're
Speaker 5: slurring, you're
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): like, baby,
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): slow right slow he's always a justification but then the problem is is the fourth phase is unconscious that's great that's the best justification
Speaker 76: for though is is unconsciousness which is a problem so what do you do then well a responsible drug act will then take cocaine to make sure you don't go in the course right so i start to balance it out the yin and the yang come on cocaine which is great works great the problem is cocaine makes
Speaker 10: you anxious so i needed xanax to get rid of the anxiety Right. So I take Xanax to call the anxiety, but I still need something to kick me over the edge
Speaker 10: with sleeping. So I took some ambient to sleep and then some morphine for the pain I had. And before I knew it, I was taking 22 drugs at the same time. I was like a human petri dish. Right.
And I
Speaker 10: was just incredibly high all the time. You're lucky you didn't die. I know. I'm very lucky. I know. I don't you know, I always wonder why I didn't have any permanent damage. Yeah. Right. I think most of it was not a big drinker. I think alcohol is like that wild card. Alcohol and quailers will kill you. Yeah. It's a it's a wild card. It's like gasoline on the fire.
Speaker 10: So I was very fortunate. I got sober in 97. How? Went to rehab. I went to rehab. I got
Speaker 78: sober. What's withdrawal like from Quaaludes?
Not
Speaker 10: bad. It wasn't that bad. You know, for me, it wasn't so much withdrawal was the problem. It was more like just I needed like an adult time out. I was so done with it. Like, I think, you know, people can get sober in rehab. Yeah.
Speaker 10: people can get sober in the rooms of Alcoholics
Speaker 76: Anonymous right you can get sober anywhere but you have to be ready to get sober yeah if you're not ready right you could be in the world's greatest rehab and you'll just relapse you'll run it you'll climb over the wall as soon as you got you'll use again worse I was done I like my life was so out of control
Speaker 10: I had my kids were starting to get older now they're four and five years old so I was like I gotta end this so I know I was very happy to stop using drugs right so that was in 97
I had a
Speaker 10: problem in 2009 where I had some
Speaker 76: terrible run of like five surgeries in this shoulder and five soldiers in this shoulder I had really bad back the whole thing so I was taking Vicodin from the doctor from the doctor right and then I got off of that and went on something called Suboxone of course which is a disaster
Speaker 10: in its own right but I could function and then I find an ibogaine
you
Speaker 10: know ibogaine yeah and I got completely that was how did that work well you know I was on this low dose of suboxone for like 10 years and it didn't affect me but it's like it's
Speaker 81: just not who why did they do that because the
Speaker 82: pharmaceutical companies make a fortune with it so they
Speaker 81: get everyone addicted to opioids
Speaker 83: can you explain yeah what that suboxone yeah so it's
a
Speaker 10: box suboxone so what happens is with the opioid crisis right everyone's taking oxycontin and percodan and and Percocet and Vicodin
and all
Speaker 10: these right and they're giving them out like
Speaker 26: they're candy all over the place.
Speaker 26: Right. So this is massive opioid crisis. Right. When they realized that especially OxyContin and fentanyl was so addictive and people were dying. They said we have to have a solution.
Speaker 9: So they put people on something called Suboxone. Suboxone is what they call a partial opioid agonist, meaning it binds to similar receptors, but it doesn't really
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): get you high.
and
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): it you can't really it's very hard to overdose on it it's like the modern methadone exactly it's exactly what it is right so it's much more long acting and you could be on it and no one knows you're on it but in your mouth maybe a little bit drier and so forth you're a little bit tighter at night but generally speaking if you're really careful then you know you can live on
Speaker 9: that and it's not the worst thing in the world does
Speaker 84: it affect your cognitive ability
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): not at a very low dose but the problem is most people don't stay at a low dose they go up and they go up because they they get a little bit of a high from it so they abuse Suboxone
and it's like a
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): life sentence and it's like you're not good for your liver it's you're taking an opioid right yeah so I was on that for a long time at a very low dose and fine saying you know what I'm just I want to be up I don't want anything in my system so I went and did Ibogaine in Mexico in Cancun which everyone you know heard of Ibogaine Ibogaine is a naturally occurring to plant right in
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): Africa hallucinogen it's a very powerful hallucinogen but for some reason it binds to the same opioid receptors as as a as morphine right and
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): you know some Vicodin,
right?
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): It resets them. So there's this weird thing. It resets you. It brings you back to pre-addiction. So when you're done with this 12-hour nasty, I mean, this trip is scary. What happens? It's not fun. Where did you do
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): it? Hotel Rupert? I did it in a clinic in Cancun called Beyond, which is, I mean, I'd recommend this place to anybody. It was amazing. And they really did an amazing job. Very safe. It's all doctors, supervisors. You always hooked
up to
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): a heart machine because it can be taught on your heart, right?
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): And they really support you emotionally, right? And when I did this... Wait, but what happened? So you take it... The guy tripped the scariest, ugliest, terrible trip. I was petrified before I started by that. You hear all these horror stories about Ibogaine, right? Where you're seeing dead people talking
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): to you and your father is talking to you from the back. My father's passed away, right? So you see all these visions and stuff and you hear a lot of noises and bugs. It's terrible. And was it as bad as you thought?
Speaker 86 (lower-pitched voice): It was pretty bad.
Speaker 86 (lower-pitched voice): It was, I was so, I was petrified. I'll admit it. I was petrified. The whole time?
The first
Speaker 86 (lower-pitched voice): six hours is brutal. The second six hours is like, get me out of this room. I'm like, you're like diaper boy. You want to
do a
Speaker 86 (lower-pitched voice): primal scream,
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): right? But, but what I did feel, no, no, it's scary as shit. All right. I'm telling you, it is not fun at all. Right. But I did
Speaker 26: feel it like burning out my wrist. I can feel it, my brain working. Like I knew it. Like I knew as it was happening, like I'm done with it. Like I'm not going to need this stuff anymore. Right.
So,
Speaker 26: So, anyway, so after it was over, like I recovered,
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): like, you know, 12
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): hours I got out, I never did another, you know, any morphine or any narcotics ever again. That was it. It was done.
Speaker 87: Amazing. Yeah, it resets your receptors. Did it affect you in any other ways? You
know,
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): some people, I think, have more of a spiritual journey because it's great for PTSD as well, like for veterans, right? So, right now, they're trying to fund studies for veterans. It's very helpful with PTSD, right? I didn't think it made that many changes in me. I was in a pretty good
place
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): place when I went in there, I just literally had a physical, like a physical addiction that if I didn't take this stupid
Speaker 22: drug, I'd get uncomfortable and I didn't want to have that. Like I'm traveling all the time. Right. So for me, you know, I didn't feel like I made any profound changes other than that, you know, for the first 45 days, I had to learn to be like completely
sober
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): again. So it was even though I had no physical, uh, withdrawals, I had some post-acute, like mental, I just didn't feel...
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Great. But then after like 45 days and suddenly all the clouds lifted and I, you know, felt terrific again. So it was an amazing gift that I gave myself. And I would strongly recommend this to anybody who's suffering from, you know, opioid addiction right now. It's
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): certainly a better solution than Suboxone. And, you know, for me, it was life changing. So it's great. And so you've never been tempted to go back to anything ever
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): again.
Speaker 88: No, never.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): No. But I mean, I wasn't even, the thing was I wasn't using Suboxone to get high.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): it was it was just a maintenance thing because i got addicted to these damn painkillers when i after my surgeries right so i was using it at a dose it wasn't like i was trying to get high so i guess if someone was like reluctantly put on suboxone because they were like a drug act and it was you know they just they had to because their life was so out of control
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): um i guess they'd have to probably work through some therapy as well afterwards but you know i think it's really helpful for that too in other words some people that go through ibogaine when they they emerge they're like they get this new perspective on their life like why would i ever want to use opioids again it's like disgusting and terrible so um but it
Speaker 34 (lower-pitched voice): is incredibly powerful like it is not no joke it is no joke like i've tried ketamine you know like it's a great thing for not use ketamine not to expand your brain i've tried other hallucinogens i've tried mushrooms right
Speaker 9: you know, Ibogaine is in a class of itself. It's like
Speaker 26: not, like no one ever abused Ibogaine. You know, like you're not doing Ibogaine. Let's have a fun
trip on
Speaker 26: Ibogaine. It's like, no, it's like,
you know,
Speaker 26: it's like, let's go to the crazy house and like, you know, hold on for dear life for 12 hours. And then all your addictions are gone. And it really, it works.
Speaker 66: It actually
Speaker 89: works. - That is wild.
-
Speaker 66: Yeah. - Do you keep in touch with anyone you were on Wall Street with? - I do, yeah. I still keep in touch with some people.
From
Speaker 26: time to time, I speak to the, you know, Danny, the Jonah Hill character.
Speaker 26: Other people that my mostly people that were my good friends before they don't speak to you know
But a
Speaker 26: lot of the people were like, you know, I mean played about 4,000 people at Stratton over the years I'm like five or six thousand people and a lot of them, you know They come and go I brought into him from time to time But you know, my new life is very different. So for the
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): last, you know, since 2009 right I've been out there
and
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): Coaching and you know mentoring entrepreneurs and on how to build businesses and how to do sales and
Speaker 33 (lower-pitched voice): increase their You know marketing capabilities, right? And I never talked about Wall Street Never like I never wrote a book and that was really
Speaker 26: my core competency, right? And what really made me do is Ozzy was my brother-in-law when I when I kind of saw him like just getting whipsawed I'm like, you know what if there's two sides that I think to
Speaker 9: retiring and being wealthy or at least comfortable one is you wanna make money when you're in your working years, right, so that's, we all have to do that
Speaker 9: to make as much money as you can. Hopefully doing something you like. That's part of the equation, right? The next part is what do you do with the money that you can save from from all the hard
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): work? How do you put that money to work in a in a very safe, responsible way that's going to outpace inflation significantly, that's going to compound and allow you when you're ready to retire, have an amazing life. I believe that people deserve that. So I look at this book is it's a gift. If you read this book, really, it's such it's a
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): It's like a blueprint and it's really simple. It's like not that complicated. But, you know, I knew that if I wrote the book in a dry way, people would not read it. So I wrote in a very funny and more story. So it'd be really engaging. But as you go through that, you get this. What I consider to be a turnkey formula
Speaker 66: for a portfolio. It's like,
Speaker 90: can I ask a dumb question? So
Speaker 91 (lower-pitched voice): the S&P 500 is 500 stocks, right?
But
Speaker 91 (lower-pitched voice): they're not all in the same tier at all. They're thriving, emerging companies churning
out a
Speaker 91 (lower-pitched voice): lot of profit and then there are a lot of older industrial companies that
Speaker 92: aren't. So why wouldn't you just make your own S&P 15 or 10 or 50? Why would you- Which ones, though?
Speaker 60: And how do you know which ones are going to win and which ones are going to lose? So
Speaker 10: here's the thing, right?
Speaker 10: human beings and even analysts, I mean, even experts just that's terrible at picking the winning stocks. It's too hard. So you're just
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): imagine everybody is trying to do the same thing. What's the next winner? What's the big winner? Right. So all the money is chasing after this pool of shares. Right. So the question is, you know, any given moment, you know, the way you know, economics would say is that the market is fairly priced in this moment based on
Speaker 76: all the available information that's out there. Yeah, this is what every single individual stock is worth. Right.
Speaker 76: now over time right when you buy the s
Speaker 10: p now remember the s p 500 is the 500 biggest most profitable companies in the u.s
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): they're in 10 different sectors but the s p the index committee every quarter will meet and say okay based on the u.s economy
the
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): weighting of each sector correct we have nothing information stocks right do we have enough in industrials how about the health care right so if you go back like 30 years industrial is one of the biggest sectors out there but then we exported our manufacturing base to China right and slowly the financials become really big and also especially computers and information and healthcare so the biggest ones are now healthcare and confused information technology those your biggest sectors so what happens is the essence people
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): reweight itself every quarter to match the US economy and any of the companies that are either underperforming, right, or becoming less relevant to their sector will be replaced by companies that are doing better and are more relevant. So you have at any given moment.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): the 500 best companies all done for you for free by the S&P index to me who's selling that information making money in a different way they don't make the money you can't invest in the S&P index because it's an index you need a fund right that so so there's a very big difference when the S&P first came out you could only watch it there was no way to invest in it it was like a benchmark how am I doing compared to the S&P you couldn't buy it you'd have to go buy each
of
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): the 500 stocks, which is a force prohibitive and not, you know, you could just time prohibitive as well. Right. So when the first S&P 500 index fund came along, it allowed people for the first time ever to buy all 500 companies in one trade, right? Which is incredibly tax efficient and time efficient. Now, what else happens once a company goes into the S&P, all the institutions have to buy it. So there's almost a self-fulfilling prophecy or part of it as well. Right. So if.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): You have information like inside information. You're one of those rare people that can somehow like one of 10 million people or that could somehow figure out which stocks are going
Speaker 9: up. We're going to beat the S&P. God bless you. Right. But my chance, the chance off to everyone listening is that's not you. Right. You're not going to be able to beat the S&P.
Speaker 93: You don't think that's
Speaker 9: me. You know, even with my Jim Cramer strategy, you don't
Speaker 37 (lower-pitched voice): think it's me. So much talent is a speaker. God would not give one man so much talent and so much insight.
Speaker 35: Fair, fair. Right. So anyway,
so, so,
Speaker 35: I really it's been proven like I'm not just saying this it's like it's been
Speaker 30: proven by every study when you read the book I go through every study
in a
Speaker 30: very funny way and then when you like the last chapter is called meet the fuckers Instead of meet the fuckers. I called meet
Speaker 26: the fuckers. So we're the fuckers. Well, the fuckers are the Jim Cramer's of the world These are all the fuckers who are out there and he's just one of all the online that Charlton's on tick-tock These five
Speaker 9: stocks about the moon
Speaker 9: I mean, come on, like this stuff is littered all over the internet. Try to bait people into making stupid investment decisions that are self-defeating. It's the seminar guy who tells you to buy the magical trading system. That's going to beat the market. You could turn $50 to $5,000
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): in three months in your bathroom from home with my algorithm. Well, that's so great. How come you're not using it yourself? Why are you fricking walking this? It's so ridiculous, but this is what people
Speaker 35: fall for it,
Speaker 95: right? They
Speaker 35: do all the time and they end up getting destroyed.
Speaker 35: And you know when it really hits them, when they're 55, 60
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): years old and they don't have the money they should have. If you follow the advice in this book, which is an arguably the best advice, Warren Buffett would give you this advice, seriously. It's an arguably
Speaker 22: great advice, and that is to play the long term investing game, relying on compounding, meaning you start off with a small, not as much as you can. Right. And
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): then add to it a little bit each month, whenever you can, as much as you can. And then also reinvest your dividends.
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): So when you get quarterly dividends, because the S&P pays a dividend,
Speaker 22: reinvest those as well. And just forget it. Don't worry about what's going on in the world. Like you say, the US economy is going to go to shit. Okay, maybe it will, maybe it won't, who knows. But here's the deal. No matter how shitty the US economy gets, you still
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): have really big companies out there that are raping and pillaging, making a fortune out there. Like even the S&P 500,
Half
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): the business is overseas. They're multinationals, right? So you're getting overseas exposure as well. And, you know, listen,
Speaker 26: I'm also, as much as America's broken, I still have a believer in the American system of capitalism. I've traveled the whole
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): world. I've never seen a country where they had this, like, the drive and the ingenuity that we have. The U.S. is a special place. I don't care what's wrong with it. It's a special place. And also
Speaker 96: compared to what? It's the best bad option out there, right?
So I
Speaker 96: really believe, and then also there's a couple other investments you want to make to balance out
Speaker 96: risk, right? You
Speaker 28 (lower-pitched voice): want to have what's called a bond fund in there. But again, none of this is about trying to pick which bonds are going to pay more than others. You can't do that. You're trading against bond professionals that are going to rip your eyeballs out every time you're trying to beat the market. So you want to be engaging in these index, let's call passive investing. Not active. Passive investing, right? It's
Speaker 91 (lower-pitched voice): exactly the opposite I told people to do when I was in my 20s. So if I could sum up your advice, it would be ignore the experts and be passive, not active.
Speaker 91 (lower-pitched voice): 100%, nor
Speaker 99: the experts, especially Jim Cramer, by the way. I call him a carnival-barking-ass clown, okay? But I mean, that's totally fair,
Speaker 96: but it's totally fair. And everyone used to, like when I was doing my legal vetting, and they got like, "No problem, man?" At least once a day,
Speaker 56: I watched Jim Cramer on Sam Bankman-Fried, just to make myself feel good. That's another story to start the whole crypto
Speaker 99: world, right, with Sam Bankman-Fried.
So
Speaker 99: he got... I mean, listen, I knew that was going to happen. I think I was asked, maybe I knew about what's going to happen with Sam Banking. I said, this guy's going to go to jail for... Listen, I don't think he deserves life in jail. No, I agree. But, you know, he's probably going to get 20 years. Very few people deserve life in prison. You know, but he's in for a world of pain.
The
Speaker 100: people who started the Iraq War do. But other than that, I agree. Jordan Belfort, thank you
Speaker 101: so much. My pleasure. Great to see you. Thanks. Thank you. Take care.
Thank you.